Guide to the Poynter Fellowship in Journalism, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Poynter Fellowship in Journalism, Yale University, records
1966-1995
RU 228
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
16
The records consist of administrative files, audiotapes, and videotapes documenting recipients of the Poynter Fellowship in Journalism at Yale University. Recipients include Steven Brill, David Gergen, and Charlayne Hunter-Gault. Also includes an audiotape of the R. Woodward Fellowship lecture, 1994.
Yale University. Office of the Secretary
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 4-A (YRG 4-A), Records of the Yale secretary's office.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of administrative files, audiotapes, and videotapes documenting recipients of the Poynter Fellowship in Journalism at Yale University. Recipients include Steven Brill, David Gergen, and Charlayne Hunter-Gault. Also includes an audiotape of the R. Woodward Fellowship lecture, 1994.
Journalism -- Scholarships, Fellowships, etc.; Lectures and lecturing; Audiotapes; Videotapes; Yale University -- Funds and scholarships; Yale University. Office of the Secretary
- R. Woodward fellowship recipient [audiorecording], 1994; Accession 1995-A-030
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - R. Woodward fellowship recipient, 1994; audiocassette (Box 1)
- Poynter Fellowship lectures, 1995; Accession 1995-A-054
- Poynter Fellowship lectures, 1995; Accession 1996-A-033
- Poynter Fellowship lectures, 1966-1982; Accession 1998-A-125
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2017
  - Subject files, Circa 1975-1982
    - Poynter Reading Project (Box 1)
    - Board of Directors (Box 1)
    - Modern Media Inst. III (Box 1)
    - Nelson Poynter (Box 1)
  - Publicity files, clippings, etc (Box 2)
  - Publicity files, clippings, etc (Box 4)
  - Publicity files, clippings, etc (Box 3)
  - Publicity files, clippings, etc. (Box 9)
  - Subject files
    - St. Petersburg Times (Box 5)
    - Yale Daily News Special Issue (Box 5)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 5)
    - Energy Symposium, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Poynter, 1975-1976 (Box 5)
    - Poynter-Vassar (Box 5)
    - Economics (Box 5)
    - MMI (Box 5)
    - Fellows, 1978-1979 (Box 6)
    - Poynter (Box 6)
  - [chaotic files] (Box 7)
  - Scrapbooks, albums (Box 8)
  - Audiorecordings
    - "Saying the Unthinkable," Part I. C.V. Woodward, Joseph Barnes, W. Uphans, 1966 January 2; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 10)
    - "The Christian and Politics" Congressman J. Brademas, Rev. A. Van Den Hewel, I. Gertzog, 1966 March 13; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 11)
    - "Why Cheer A Loser?" Henry Chauncey, Jr., P. Weiss, Delaney Kiphuth, 1967 May 12 (Box 12)
    - "Renewal: Roman Catholicism and the Third Man" Rev. G. Baum, Rev. P.S. Minear, Rev. I.D.K. Siggins, Rev. A Brandenburg, 1969 January 17; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 13)
    - "The 91st Congress and the Presidency" A.M. Bickel, R.A. Dahl, J.G. Deutsch, 1969 January 24; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 14)
    - "Physical Mobility and Social Change" H. Wexler, S. Chermayeff, J. McHale, 1969 January 31; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 15)
    - "Economics of the City" J.R. Meyer, J. Tobin, K. Kain, 1969 February 7; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 16)
    - "Economics and History" H.N. Parker, H.A. Kiskimin, Jr., 1969 February 14; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 17)
    - "Public Employees and the Law" H.H. Wellington, E.J. Phelps, R.K. Winter", 1969 February 21; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 18)
    - "Public Employees and the Law" H.H. Wellington, E.J. Phelps, R.K. Winter", 1969 February 21; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 19)
    - Parker Po-Fei Hwang, senior lecturer, reading Chinese poetry, 1974; audiocassette (Box 20)
    - Hernandez, governor of Puerto Rico, press conference, 1974; audiocassette (Box 21)
    - Wolfgang Leonard, adjunct professor of history interview (on Brandt), 1974; audiocassette (Box 23)
    - Reverend Jesse Jackson press conference, 1974; audiocassette (Box 24)
    - John Ottina, commisioner of education, interview, 1974; audiocassette (Box 25)
    - Christof Penderecki, composer, interview, 1974; audiocassette (Box 27)
    - Gloria Steinem, editor magazine, press conference, 1974; audiocassette (Box 28)
    - Robert Strauss, chairman of Democratic Party, press conference, 1974; audiocassette (Box 29)
    - Louis Heilprin Pollak, law professor, interview, 1974; audiocassette (Box 30)
    - Elliot Richardson, press conference, 1974; audiocassette (Box 31)
    - Eugene McCarthy, interview and speech, 1974; audiocassette (Box 32)
    - Eugene McCarthy, interview and speech, 1974; audiocassette (Box 33)
    - Senator Sam Ervin, press conference, 1974 Spring; audiocassette (Box 36)
    - Spokesman for the Third World Coalition, on Shockley, 1974 Spring; audiocassette (Box 37)
    - Senator Sam Ervin, talk with students and interview with Flink, 1974 February 12-13; audiocassette (Box 38)
    - Senator Sam Ervin, talk with students and interview with Flink, 1974 February 12-13; audiocassette (Box 39)
    - Chubb Fellows: Elliot Richardson and panel", 1974 April 1; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 40)
    - Chubb Fellows: Elliot Richardson and panel", 1974 April 1; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 41)
    - Jane Fonda, press conference, 1974 October 28; audiocassette (Box 42)
    - Clarence Kelley, FBI head, press conference, 1974 November 5; audiocassette (Box 43)
    - Archibald Cox, press conference, 1974 Winter; audiocassette (Box 44)
    - Congressman Jerome Waldie, interview, 1974 November 11; audiocassette (Box 45)
    - Yale Reports 75 #1, 1975; audiocassette (Box 46)
    - Yale Reports 75 #15, 1975; audiocassette (Box 47)
    - Ben Bradlee, editor of, interviewed by Stanley Flink, 1975; audiocassette (Box 48)
    - Dean Rusk, press conference, 1975 Spring; audiocassette (Box 49)
    - Wlater Wriston, chairman of Citicorp, press conference, 1975 Spring; audiocassette (Box 50)
    - Fawaz Turki, speech to the Political Union, 1975 Spring; audiocassette (Box 51)
    - Manuel Puig, Argentinian novelist, interviewed by Tom Anderson, 1975 Spring; audiocassette (Box 52)
    - Judge Wright, press conference; Jacque Soustelle, French deputy and anthropologist, interview, 1975 Spring; audiocassette (Box 53)
    - Reverend Lucius Walker, speech to Yale Hunger Action Project (YHAP) on hunger in America, 1975 Spring; audiocassette (Box 54)
    - John Sawhill, energy czar, speech to Political Union, 1975 Spring; audiocassette (Box 55)
    - Roderick Nash, environmentalist, speech at School of Forestry and Environmental Studies on wilderness, 1975 Spring; audiocassette (Box 56)
    - Alan Berg, speech for Yale Hunger Action Project (YHAP), 1975 Spring; audiocassette (Box 57)
    - Frank Press, professor at MIT, interviewed by Paula Checkoway on earthquakes, 1975 January; audiocassette (Box 58)
    - Senator Ted Kennedy, speech at Medical School, 1975 January; audiocassette (Box 59)
    - Senator Ted Kennedy, speech at Medical School, 1975 January; audiocassette (Box 60)
    - Harry Magdoff, author, speech sponsored by Afro American Cultural Center on China, 1975 January; audiocassette (Box 61)
    - Harry Magdoff, author, speech sponsored by Afro American Cultural Center on China, 1975 January; audiocassette (Box 62)
    - Vernon Bellecourt, representative of American Indian Movement, speech to Political Union, 1975 January; audiocassette (Box 63)
    - Vernon Bellecourt, representative of American Indian Movement, speech to Political Union, 1975 January; audiocassette (Box 64)
    - Andre Wina?, Oedipus lecture, 1975 January 15; audiocassette (Box 65)
    - John Lindsay, press conference, 1975 January 16; audiocassette (Box 66)
    - Mario Soares, leader of Portuguese Socialist Party, press conference, 1975 January 21; audiocassette (Box 67)
    - George Ball, press conference, 1975 January 21; audiocassette (Box 68)
    - George Ball, speech to Yale Political Union, 1975 January 21; audiocassette (Box 69)
    - Nathaniel Reed, assistant secretary of the interior, speech to Political Union, 1975 January 29; audiocassette (Box 70)
    - George Silver, professor of public health, Yale Medical School, interview, 1975 January 29; audiocassette (Box 71)
    - Maxwell, 3rd year law student, interviewed by Tom Anderson, 1975 February; audiocassette (Box 72)
    - Margot, poetry reading at third world women's conference, 1975 February; audiocassette (Box 73)
    - Abba Eban, Arnold Wolfer's lecture, Pierson College, 1975 February; audiocassette (Box 74)
    - Joe Bishop, professor at Yale Law School, interviewed by Tom Anderson (on the CIA), 1975 February; audiocassette (Box 75)
    - Dr. Talbot, lecture at School of Forestry on the resources of the sea, 1975 February; audiocassette (Box 76)
    - Joseph Alsop, columnist, speech to Political Union, 1975 March; audiocassette (Box 77)
    - George Plimpton at Thursday Club, 1975 March 6; audiocassette (Box 78)
    - John Roberts, assistant dean of Yale Law School, interview (on President Ford's visit), 1975 April; audiocassette (Box 79)
    - Dick Cavett, Christopher Porterfield, informal talk in Calhoun Colledge dining hall, 1975 April; audiocassette (Box 81)
    - Dick Cavett, Christopher Porterfield, informal talk in Calhoun Colledge dining hall, 1975 April; audiocassette (Box 82)
    - Roy Wilkins, chairman NAACP, speech to Political Union, 1975 April; audiocassette (Box 83)
    - John Brooks, talk in Calhoun College, 1975 April; audiocassette (Box 84)
    - Nancy Milio, Sybil Palmer Bellos lecture at the Yale School of Nursing, 1975 April 9; audiocassette (Box 86)
    - Tom Winship, editor, talk at Thursday Club, 1975 April 10; audiocassette (Box 87)
    - Sadat Hassan, permanent representative of PLO to UN, speech to Political Union, 1975 April 14; audiocassette (Box 88)
    - Sadat Hassan, permanent representative of PLO to UN, speech to Political Union, 1975 April 14; audiocassette (Box 89)
    - Adam Clymer, journalist, interview, 1975 April 16; audiocassette (Box 90)
    - Peter Davis, "Hearts and Minds," audiocassette, 1975 April 17 (Box 91)
    - Abba Eban, guest of Political Union, press conference, 1975 April 18; audiocassette (Box 92)
    - Roy Wilkins, chairman of NAACP, press conference, 1975 April 21; audiocassette (Box 93)
    - Ella Grasso, seminar in Calhoun College, 1975 April 23; audiocassette (Box 94)
    - Newsmen at New Haven airport for President Ford's visit (includes Pierpoint and Brokaw), 1975 April 26; audiocassette (Box 95)
    - Urie Bronfenbrenner, Cornell University, "Family Workshop," audiocassette, 1975 June 18 (Box 96)
    - Strobe Talbott, "Covering KIssinger," audiocassette, 1975 June 26 (Box 97)
    - Owen Lattimer, "China: A View Landward," audiocassette, 1975 July 23 (Box 98)
    - George May, on the Englightenment, 1975 July 28; audiocassette (Box 99)
    - Russell Train, "Environmental Issues and Public Policy," audiocassette, 1975 August 6 (Box 101)
    - "Pantechnicon", new music shindig, 1975 August 7; audiocassette (Box 102)
    - Edward Heath, press conference, 1975 September 15; audiocassette (Box 104)
    - Mel Elfin, Washington bureau chief, 1975 September 22; audiocassette (Box 105)
    - Dr. Benjamin Spock, guest of Liberal Party, "Future of Democracy," audiocassette, 1975 October 1 (Box 106)
    - Gil Jones, IBM world trade chairman, "7 Myths about Multi-Nationals," audiocassette, 1975 October 7 (Box 107)
    - Governor David Boren, speech to Political Union on states rights, 1975 October 5; audiocassette (Box 108)
    - S.E.F. interviews David Boren, Governor of Oklahoma, 1975 October 6; audiocassette (Box 109)
    - Nguyen Cao Ky, press conference, 1975 October 23; audiocassette (Box 110)
    - Nguyen Cao Ky, press conference, 1975 October 23; audiocassette (Box 111)
    - Brother David Steindl-Rast, 1975 October 23; audiocassette (Box 112)
    - David Rockefeller, speech, Davies Auditorium, 1975 November 6; audiocassette (Box 114)
    - Bob Woodward, "After Watergate," audiocassette, 1975 November 6 (Box 115)
    - Dale Bumpers, 1975 November 17; audiocassette (Box 118)
    - Dr. Shear on Transcendental Meditation, 1975 November 20; audiocassette (Box 119)
    - Francis Mergen "The Alaskan Pipeline: Ecological, Social and Economic Implications," audiocassette, 1975 November 25 (Box 120)
    - Harrington, Ackerman, Pincus, "Congressional CIA Investigations," audiocassette, 1975 December 1 (Box 121)
    - Hendrick Smith, report on Russia, 1975 December 4; audiocassette (Box 124)
    - Richard Avedon, photographer, Calhoun Master's Tea, 1975 December 10; audiocassette (Box 125)
    - "Public and the Purse", 1975-1976; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 146)
    - "Public and the Purse", 1975-1976; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 147)
    - Penelope Giliat reading her story, "As Freud has taught us, there are no jokes," audiocassette, 1976 Spring (Box 126)
    - Stephan Folz, "Problems of Democracy in the Third World," audiocassette, 1976 Spring (Box 127)
    - John Ashberry with E. Kown? and H. Bloom, 1976 Spring; audiocassette (Box 128)
    - "Understanding the Facts," Davis, 1976 January 20; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 151)
    - "Understanding the Facts," Davis, 1976 January 20; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 152)
    - "Understanding an Issue", 1976 January 20; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 153)
    - "Understanding an Issue", 1976 January 20; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 154)
    - "Understanding an Issue", 1976 January 20; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 155)
    - "Understanding the Economists", 1976 January 21; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 156)
    - "Understanding the Economists", 1976 January 21; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 157)
    - "Understanding the Economists", 1976 January 21; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 158)
    - "Understanding the Economists", 1976 January 21; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 159)
    - John Cunniff, Associated Press, on the economy, 1976 January 21; audiocassette (Box 130)
    - Mario Soares, leader of the Socialist Party of Portugal, interviewed by S.E.F., 1976 January 26; audiocassette (Box 131)
    - Joseph Biden, speech to Political Union, 1976 February 10; audiocassette (Box 132)
    - James Schlesinger, interviewed by S.E.F, 1976 February 12; audiocassette (Box 133)
    - James Schlesinger, Chubb Fellow, 1976 February 12; audiocassette (Box 134)
    - N. Scott Momaday, 1976 February 23; audiocassette (Box 135)
    - Robert Strauss, press conference, 1976 February 26; audiocassette (Box 136)
    - Robert Strauss, speech to Political Union, 1976 February 26; audiocassette (Box 137)
    - Andrew Young, Georgia congressman, speech to BLSU, 1976 March 8; audiocassette (Box 138)
    - Yale's 275th birthday, 1976 October 15; audiocassette (Box 145)
    - Sara S. Sparrow, "Why Children Don't Learn," audiocassette, 1976 October 15 (Box 148)
    - B. Geller, Wednesday Club, 1976 December; audiocassette (Box 150)
    - Cesar Pelli, Wednesday Club, 1977 January; audiocassette (Box 160)
    - Kingman Brewster, press conference, 1977 January 18; audiocassette (Box 161)
    - Kingman Brewster, press conference, 1977 January 18; audiocassette (Box 162)
    - George Bush, press conference, 1977 January 26; audiocassette (Box 163)
    - Kingman Brewster interview with, 1977 March 1; audiocassette (Box 164)
    - "TV and American Culture", 1977 November 21; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 185)
    - "TV and American Culture", 1977 November 21; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 186)
    - Norman Lear, 1977 November 22; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 187)
    - "Revolution in Publishing,", 1979 January 18; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 189)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 189U)
    - "Revolution in Publishing", 1979 January 18; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 190)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 190U)
    - "Revolution in Publishing", 1979 January 18; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 191)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 191U)
    - "Revolution in Publishing", 1979 January 18; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 192)
      - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 192U)
    - Grulion?, 1979 April 16; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 196)
    - Dmitri Ivanov, "The World of the Vatican - A Journalist's Perspective," audiocassette, 1981 April 2 (Box 166)
    - Jane, Brody, "Getting the Word Out on Healthy Living", 1981 October 28; audiocassette (Box 167)
    - Jacobo Timerman, Stiles dining hall, 1981 November 4; audiocassette (Box 168)
    - Jacobo Timerman, Trumbull common room, 1981 November 5; audiocassette (Box 169)
    - Jacobo Timerman, Trumbull common room, 1981 November 5; audiocassette (Box 170)
    - "Is Science on TV Truly Educational or Superficial," Pierson Master's Tea, 1981 November 11; audiocassette (Box 171)
    - W. Sullivan, Silliman Master's Tea, 1981 November 18; audiocassette (Box 172)
    - W. Sullivan, Silliman Master's Tea, 1981 November 18; audiocassette (Box 173)
    - John F. Lehman, "The Press and the Pentagon", 1982 January 28; audiocassette (Box 175)
    - John F. Lehman, "The Press and the Pentagon", 1982 January 28; audiocassette (Box 176)
    - Brutus Coste, conversation with Political Union, Undated; audiocassette (Box 179)
    - Leon Katz, drama critic on Gertrude Stein's dramatic theory, Undated; audiocassette (Box 180)
    - Fred Norris, democratic presidential hopeful, Undated; audiocassette (Box 181)
    - Sir George Godber, "England's National Health ?", Undated; audiocassette (Box 183)
    - Herbert Ma, "Law and Social Change: Some Recent Chinese Experiences," audiocassette, Undated (Box 184)
    - Eleanor Holmes Norton, Undated; audiocassette (Box 200)
    - Kenneth Kirkwood, Rhodesia, Undated; audiocassette (Box 202)
    - Morton Halperin, Brookings Institute, on intelligence organizations, Undated; audiocassette (Box 203)
    - Erik Eckholm on ecology and food, Undated; audiocassette (Box 204)
    - Edward Osborn Wilson, professor of Zoology, Harvard University, "Sociobiology: The New Synthesis", Undated; audiocassette (Box 205)
    - Patricia Wald, "Mental Health and Law", Undated; audiocassette (Box 206)
    - Discussion with Fred Freed on his film "Blue Collar Trap" (1974), December 4; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 207)
    - Discussion with Fred? Freed on the decision to drop the bomb, December 4; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 208)
    - Unidentified, Undated; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 209)
    - Unidentified panel (roll IV), Undated; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 210)
  - Posters (Box 211)
- Poynter Fellowship films, circa 1973; Accession 2004-A-063
  - Unidentified, sound reel (16mm) (Box 1)
  - Unidentified panel, film and sound reels (16mm) (Box 2)
  - Montgomery?, film reel (16mm) (Box 3)
  - Unidentified panel, sound reel (16mm) (Box 4)
  - Unidentified panel, film reel (16mm) (Box 5)
- Scrapbook concerning the Poynter Fellowship, 1978-1979; Accession 2004-A-066
  - Scrapbook concerning the Poynter Fellowship, 1978-1979 (Box 1)